A Guide to the Charles Olson Research Collection 1969.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Charles Olson Research Collection
1910-1970
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1969.0001
130 Linear Feet
The Charles Olson Research Collection contains the literary works, correspondence, photographs, and personal, professional, and family papers of writer and poet Charles Olson. This collection also includes some administrative records of Black Mountain College.
Biography
Charles Olson was born in Worcester, Massachusetts, on 27 December 1910, to Karl Joseph and Mary Hines Olson. He attended Wesleyan University where he received a B.A. in 1932 and a M.A. in 1933. He continued his graduate studies at Harvard University from 1936 to 1938. His daughter Katherine was born during his first marriage, to Constance Wilcock. His second marriage, to Elizabeth Kaiser, produced a son, Charles Peter. Elizabeth, or Betty as she was known to her friends, died tragically in a car accident in March 1964. Charles Olson received several prestigious awards during his long career, including two Guggenheim Fellowships, in 1939 and 1948; a Wenner-Gren Foundation grant in 1952; a Longview Foundation award for The Maximus Poems in 1961; and an Oscar Blumenthal Prize (Poetry magazine), 1965. Charles Olson died from cancer on 10 January 1970.
Scope and Content
The Charles Olson Research Collection features a wide range of materials covering such diverse topics as the Life and Works of Herman Melville, Black Mountain College, the Beat Generation, the Office of Wartime Information, and the Literary and Cultural Revolution of the 1960's. Correspondents of note include T.S. Eliot, Allen Ginsberg, LeRoi Jones, and Ezra Pound. The collection includes Olson's prose and poetry, correspondence with more than 1500 individuals, documents and ephemera from Olson's personal life, family papers, photographs, newspapers, atlases, books, journals and records from Black Mountain College. The bulk of the collection dates from Olson's lifetime, 1910-1970. However, as the Archives and Special Collections continued collecting donations from friends, acquaintances and family members after Olson's death, some items in the collection date from after Olson's death.
Arrangement
Series I: Works (undated, 1927-1969) include manuscripts of poetry and essays, project notes, notebooks, diaries, subject files, and fragments. Manuscripts of published poetry are arranged according to the critical edition in which they are collected. Series II: Correspondence (undated, 1910-1970) encompasses over 10,000 items, including letters, postcards, telegrams, manuscripts, clippings, and manuscript envelopes. All items are filed alphabetically by last name of sender, including outgoing correspondence from Olson. Outgoing correspondence is subdivided and arranged alphabetically according to the last name of the recipient. Series III: Personal and Professional Papers (undated, 1910-1970) contain juvenilia, academic materials, financial documents, and ephemera. This series is arranged by topic, then chronologically. Series IV: Family Papers (undated) include documents relating to Olson's parents, wives and children, including his father's philatelic materials and Betty Kaiser's diaries. Series V: Photographs (undated) contains more than 200 photographs of Charles Olson and his family, friends and correspondents. The Collection includes original photographs owned by Charles Olson, original photographs or copies of original prints donated to the Archives, and reference prints (copies) made by the Archives for publication or preservation. Photographs are divided into eight sub-series: Photographs taken by Charles Olson; Photographs of Charles Olson (alone and in groups); Olson's family; Friends and associates; Black Mountain College; Gloucester; Miscellaneous photographs owned by Charles Olson; and Copy prints of manuscripts. Series VI: Black Mountain College Records contains some official records from Black Mountain College, including student applications and financial records. Series VII: Ephemera contains a wide range of items, including objects such as Olson's typewriter and tarot cards. Paper ephemera is arranged by year; other objects are simply listed according to their placement on the shelves. Series VIII: Related Materials contains materials related to Charles Olson that were donated to the University of Connecticut by individuals following Charles Olson's death. These materials may include correspondence (often between Olson and the donor), Olson manuscripts, and other items of interest. These materials are arranged by the last name of the donor.
Separated Material
Archives & Special Collections and the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries, also maintains Charles Olson's personal library. While the library is not described here as part of the papers, it should be regarded as an important primary source. A full listing of Olson's library is available in the UConn Library online catalog.
Restrictions on Access
By stipulation of some donors, some materials are restricted from research use. Consult with the Curator for further information.
Acquisition Information
The Charles Olson Papers were purchased by the University of Connecticut from the Estate of Charles Olson in 1972. The University also purchased from the Estate the literary rights to all of Olson's writing that remained unpublished at the time of his death. Since then, the original papers have been augmented by numerous additions through purchase and by gift. In 2003, the decision was made to rename the papers The Charles Olson Research Collection to better describe the scope and content of the collection. Researchers should consult with the Curator to establish the provenance of any particular document.
Administrative records; Maps (documents); Photographs; Publications (documents); Notebooks; Correspondence; Typescripts; Photocopies; Notes; Gloucester (inhabited place); Monographs; Sketches; Poems; Manuscripts (document genre); Newsletters; Newspapers; Poets; Broadsides (notices); Galley proofs; School Records; Works of Art; Financial Records; Diaries; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970; Black Mountain College (Black Mountain, N.C.)
- Series I: Works, undated, 1927-1969
  - A. Maximus Poems
    General note
    Individual poems are filed in order of appearance in The Maximus Poems, ed. George F. Butterick (Berkeley: University of California Press, 1983)
    - Epigraph to the Maximus Poems. Typescript. 4p., June 1, 1953. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - I, Maximus. Typescript. 4p., May 1950. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - I, Maximus. Photocopy. 3p., May 17, 1950. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Notes on the Maximus Poems "from 22 on." Manuscript/Photocopy. 28p., 1953. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - I, Maximus, of Gloucester, to you. Typescript. 4p., May 1950. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Maximus Poems 1-10. Proofs. 47p. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - I, Maximus of Gloucester, to You. Galley Proof. 1p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Maximus Poems 1-10. Typescript/Carbon copy. 67p., ca. 1953. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester: Letter 2. Typescript/Carbon copy. 5p., June 2, 1951. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester, Letter 3. Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Songs of Maximus. Typescript. 7p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Maximus Letter 5. Manuscript/Typescript. 9p., ca. 1953. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letter 6. Typescript. 3p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letter 7. Manuscript/Typescript. 6p. Manuscript written on envelope, dated April 2, 1953, from the National Bank of Washington to CO., ca. 1953. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tyrian Businesses. Typescript. 8p. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letter 9. Typescript/Photocopy. 14p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letter 10. Typescript/Photocopy. 14p. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - To Gloucester - Letter 11. Manuscript/Typescript. 24p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Maximus, to Himself. Typescript/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Song and Dance of. Typescript/Carbon copy. 15p. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Maximus to Gloucester: Letter 14. Typescript/Carbon copy. 21p. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester, Letter 15. Typescript. 9p. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letter 16. Typescript. 11p. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - The Twist. Typescript. 4p., January 10, 1954. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - On First Looking Out of Juan De La Cosa's Eyes. Typescript/Carbon copy. 21p. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester, Letter 19 (A Pastoral Letter. Typescript. 5p. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Letter 20 - not a pastoral letter. Typescript. 3p. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Maximus, at Tyre, and Boston, wherever. Typescript. 1p. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Letter 22. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Letter 25. Manuscript/Typescript. 16p. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - A Plantation a beginning. Typescript. 7p. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester [I don't mean, just like that, to put down...]. Typescript. 2p. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - History is the Memory of Time. Typescript/Carbon copy. 6p. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - So Sassafras. Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - The Picture. Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - The Record. Manuscript/Typescript/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Some Good News. Empty. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Stiffening, in the Master Founders' Wills. Manuscript/Typescript. 12p. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Capt Christopher Levett (of York). Manuscript/Typescript/Carbon copy. 16p. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 1st Letter on Georges. Typescript. 4p. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - [2nd Letter on Georges.] Typescript/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - John Burke. Manuscript/Typescript. 7p. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Letter, May 2, 1959. Manuscript/Typescript/Carbon copy. 35p. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester, Sunday, July 19. Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - April Today Main Street. Manuscript/Carbon copy. 20p. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Letter 41 [broken off]. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Maximus, From Dogtown - I. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 25p., November 20, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - All My Life I've Heard About Many. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p., November 29, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - A Note on the Above. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p., November 29, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Maximus, From Dogtown - II. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 21p. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Maximus, to himself, as of "Phoenicians." Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., December 22, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Maximus further on (December 28th 1959). Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p., December 28, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - For "Moira." Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., December 15, 1959. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Maximus to Gloucester, Letter 27. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 25p. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - The River - 1. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 7p., ca. October 21, 1960. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - The River - 2. Manuscript/Photocopy. 4p., November 14, 1960. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - The Poimanderes... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., Spring 1960. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Dogtown the dog town... Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Cashes. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Like Mr. Pester acknowledges his sinfulness... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Of old times, there was a very beautiful woman... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 12p. 1 page of manuscript written on the back of a letter, dated July 11, to CO from "John" [Weiners?]. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - They said she went off fucking every Sunday. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - A Maximus. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy/Proof. 6p., August 13. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - December, 1960. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 38p. (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Maximus Letter No. whatever. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 3p. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Maximus, March 1961 - 1. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon Copy. 7p. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Maximus, March 1961 - 2. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 9p. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - The Account Book of B Ellery. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - A Maximus Song. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., March 13, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Later Tyrian Business. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 5p., March 12, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - For Robt Duncan, who understands what's going on - written because of him. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 34p., March 17, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - O John Josselyn you. Typescript/Photocopy. 20p. (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Further Completion of Plat. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - A Prayer, to the Lord... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., March 28, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Bohlin 1. Manuscript/Typescript. 25p. (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Bohlin 2. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., March 1961. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Gee avenue, what I call the upper road... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - B. Ellery Cinvat Bridge aer. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - The winning Thing. Manuscript/Typescript. 11p., 1962-1963. (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Bailyn shows sharp rise... Manuscript/Typescript/Carbon copy. 3p., ca. January 4, 1964. (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - 23 School and 16 Columbia... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., May 1, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - The bottom backward... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Jl 17 1961. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., July 17, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Letter 72. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 13p. (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - The View - July 29, 1961. Manuscript/Typescript. 37p. (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Descartes soldier... Manuscript/Typescript. 6p., September 10, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - In the interleaved Almanacks for 1646 and 1647 of Danforth. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 5p. (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Ta meteura... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Thurs Sept 14th 1961. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 28p., September 14, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Of the Parsonses. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 12p., September 29, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - The Beginnings. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p., October 15, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - On Bemo Ledge he fell... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 7p. (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - The Cut. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 8p., October 18, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Scheria - ? Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p., October 18, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - My Carpenter's Son's Son's Will. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Maximus, at the Harbor. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., October 23 and 4, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Brang that thing out... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., December 3, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Going Right out of the Century. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p., November 19, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - A Later Note on Letter No. 15. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Proof. Manuscript on envelope from New England Electric System to Betty Olson. 6p., January 15, 1962. (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - 128 a mole... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. Manuscript on envelope from Addison Gilbert Hospital. 4p. (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - "View": fr the Orontes, fr where Typhon. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., January 15, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - The East Gloucester Young Ladies Independent Society... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., October 2, 1960. (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Patriotism is the preserved park... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. Manuscript of poem written on letter, dated June 8, 1960, to President, Black Mountain College, from Leo Marcus, President of Girltown Inc. (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Bk ii chapter 37. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Galley Proof. 11p. Manuscript of poem written on back of manuscript of note, undated, from CO to Jean Katz. (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - The rocks in Settlement Cove... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - My memory is the history of time. Typescript/Manuscript/Photocopy. 3p. (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Peloria... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., November 12, 1961. (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - In the Face of a Chinese View of the City. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 12p., January 5, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Shag Rock... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p. (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - While on Obadiah Bruen's Island... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p. Manuscript poem written on back of note, undated, from "the Snowbird" to CO and Betty. (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - A 'learned man' sd Strabo... Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., January 17, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Cyprus, the strangled Aphrodite... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p., January 17, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - After the storm was over... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., January 17, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - To travel Typhon from the old holdings... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., January 18, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Up the steps, along the porch... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., January 18, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - People want delivery... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., January 18, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - The Coast goes from Hurrian Hazzi to Tyre... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p., January 19, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Tesserae. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p. Manuscript poem written on back of letter, undated, to CO from Oyez Press., January 19, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Lane's eye-view of Gloucester... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p. (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Older than Byblos... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Chronicles. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 13p., January 23, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Sanuncthion lived before the Trojan War... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 9p. (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - John Watts took salt... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - 3rd letter on Georges. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 16p. (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - The Gulf of Maine. Manuscript/Typescript. 9p. (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Existed 3000 BC? Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. Manuscript written on statement of earnings for the Italian edition of The Distances, from Grove Press, Inc., dated 1962. (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Phalaropes... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 7p. (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Aristotle and Augustine... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 9p., ca. April 1962. (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Off-upland... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., June 17, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - The earth with a city in her hair... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., September 29, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - So now let all the ships come in... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 8p. (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - HEPIT-NAGA-ATOSIS. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., October 11 or 13, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Barbara Ellis, ramp. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., October 12, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - The diadem of the Dog... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., October 19, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - They brawled on the streets... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p., November 5, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Out over the land skope view... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 12p., November n.y. (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Part of the Flower of Gloucester. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Veda upanishad edda than. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 3p. (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Wrote my first poems... Typescript/Photocopy. 4p., November n.y. (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - The 1st lot from the Cutt... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p. (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - I am the Gold Machine... Alternative title: Almadine. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p., November 19, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - In the harbor... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p., November 23, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Kent Circle Song. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 8p. (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - I swung out... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 5p. Manuscript on flattened box of Robt. Burns Cigarillos. (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - JW (from the Danelaw)... Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., November 23, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Proem. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 19p., November 21, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Not the intaglio method... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 9p., November 23, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - The Battle of the Small Animals. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p., November 25, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Monday, November 26th, 1962. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., November 26, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - He who walks with his house on... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., November 27, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - She who met the serpent in the pond... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., November 27, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - The woman who said she went out every Sunday... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., November 27, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Into the stream... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. Manuscript written on Western Union Telegram envelope. (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - The Frontlet. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 9p. Manuscript written on Tish 15, A Poetry Newsletter - Vancouver, dated November 14, 1962., December 9, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Homo Anthropos... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p., January 10, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - To enter into their bodies... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 12p., January 23, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - The Cow of Dogtown. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 31p., February 11, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Stage Fort Park. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 12p., January 4, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Further Completion of Plat (before they drown Dogtown with a reservoir, and beautify it. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 19p., February 16, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Sequentior. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. Manuscript written on envelope, dated November 29, 1962, from YMCA Cape Ann to CO., February 22, 1963. (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Licked man (as such)... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. Manuscript written together with manuscript by Peter Olson. (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Gylfaginning VI. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Heaven as sky is made of stone... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 4p. (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - All night long I was a Eumolpidae... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. Manuscript written on envelope, dated February 27, 1963, from Ronald Johnson to CO. (Box 3, Folder 164)